Okay, that's all fine and dandy, but
what we really wanted to do was we
wanted to edit the HTML page. And if we
want to do that, then we need some way
of accessing items on the HTML page. Um,
you will have noticed that I added this
thing right here called an ID. What it
does is it helps me identify an
individual element on the screen. And
that is the easiest way to access an
element on the screen. So, if I want to
access this input tag, the easiest way
to access it is by its ID. So, what I'm
going to do right here is I'm going to
access it. So, where is that ID? Well,
it's in my HTML page. How do I access my
HTML page? Well, if you think back to a
couple videos ago, I said the way we
interact with HTML from JavaScript is
using the document object model. Um, in
other words, we need to access the
document. So, the way you do that is you
say document.
And now we've accessed the document. And
then we can say getelement by ID. This
is a function and the input it takes is
it takes an ID. So the ID of this input
is high. So I'm going to access it by
high. But what is this actually give us?
Well, I'm going to console.log this when
the page loads. So console.log
document.getelement by ID. Hi. And we'll
come over here and we see that it logged
out
the entire input box.
Um, so that's great. Um, so it logged
out the input box. Um, sometimes my
browser um will log out the input box
and other times it will log out the
object itself. So I'm just going to
reload until it gives me what I want.
Okay. So what it does is it goes out and
it grabs the input element. The input
element is an object just like any other
object you've worked with. And we can
actually open this up and we can see
that it has a bunch of keys and a bunch
of values.
Um so for example
um it has an on mouse enter key and the
value it's storing is a function. Um
if we look at the ID key
we can see that the ID is high. So this
is an object and just like any other
object we can access its attributes like
we access its ID and we can change its
attributes and that will be the subject
of the next Here.